Contact

6823139204 (Mobile) dave.shubham@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/daveshubham (LinkedIn) dave-shubham.github.io/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Transact-SQL (T-SQL)
Project Management
JavaScript

Languages

English

Hindi

Gujarati

Certifications

MCSA: SQL 2016 Database Development - Certified 2017

AngularJS For Beginners

Tableau 10 A-Z: Hands-On Tableau Training For Data Science

Exam 767: Implementing a Data Warehouse

vvarenouse

Google Ads Search

Honors-Awards

New Dean's Excellence Scholarship Hasnain and Rashida Saboowala International Merit Scholarship Beta Gamma Sigma Honor Society Inductee

Shubham Dave

Programmer Analyst | Software Developer | Business Intelligence | Web & Data Analytics | Microsoft SQL Certified

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Summary

As a firm believer in "Learning is forever", I continuously pursue learning, both formally and informally. Due to strong predilection for computers since childhood, I graduated in Information Technology from Nirma University. Apart from that, I am active participant in coding sites like HackerRank, Project Euler & HackerEarth and I completed CS50 course and "Statistics and R" course by Harvard University.

After graduating, I wanted to learn about the practical application of everything I learnt and so, I joined MAQ Software Pvt. Ltd., a 9-time honoree of Inc. 5000 companies. I worked on a diverse set of projects for handling ETLs, DB management & administration, generating user analytics, UI development, automated testing and other such areas for both frontend and backend solutions. Besides working for projects, I also managed my time and successfully completed 3 Microsoft certifications. Also, I worked in support request team, which helped in improving my customer service skills and aided in understanding the perspective of clients and customers better.

This experience made me understand my affinity to work with a company that creates creative solutions and has great impact in their customers' lives. However, I wanted to further improve upon my techno-management skills and subsequently, I joined IT and Management course at UT Dallas in Fall of 2017. I am planning to complete my graduation and pursue a career in a tech based customer centric company that creates innovative solutions.

Besides my work-life, I am an avid reader and love cycling & rock climbing.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Database: MS SQL Server | MySQL

Data Visualization: Power BI | Excel Pivot | Tableau

ETL, Database Development and Performance Tuning: SSIS |

SSMS

Application Performance Management: Application Insights | Stream

Analytics

API: Web API (C#)

Web Development: HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | jQuery | AngularJS

General Programming: Java | C# | Python

Experience

Cityon Systems, Inc.
Programmer Analyst
June 2019 - Present
Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Working as a Programmer Analyst to create software solutions to help the clients achieve success and profitability in their business

The University of Texas at Dallas 1 year

Lead Parking Enforcement Officer August 2018 - May 2019 (10 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

- Provide key insights and statistical data to supervisors to improve operations of all facilities of P&T department
- Supervise and support all the Parking Enforcement Officers (PEO)
- Provide weekly scheduling of PEOs
- Training new members of PEOs and Lead PEOs
- Issue event permits for all events happening around the campus including special events such as Graduation Ceremony or VIP parking reservations
- Act as a University Ambassador by providing information and assistance to all customers
- Responsible for providing accurate information to PEOs to issue parking warning and citations in accordance with UTD Parking Rules and Regulations
- Manage departmental inventory for PEOs
- Maintain parking lots, parking meters and parking signage, reporting any inoperative meters or sign damage observed

Parking Enforcement Officer

June 2018 - August 2018 (3 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

- Responsible for field patrol of UTD parking locations and zones
- Issue parking warning and citations in accordance with UTD parking rules and regulations
- Inform management about levels of utilization and any issues that need to be addressed
- Monitor parking meters and parking regulation signage, reporting any inoperative meters or sign damage observed
- · Act as a university ambassador, providing information and assistance
- · Guide or assist with training beginner staff
- Assist with special event parking such as graduation or VIP parking reservations

MAQ Software

Software Engineer

August 2016 - August 2017 (1 year 1 month)

Mumbai Area, India

- Architected database design for large scale web applications to present multidimensional data
- Created and enhanced high-performant stored procedures, views based on multiple queries and functions for large scale web apps displaying high volume BI data
- Implemented cross-browser compatible UI using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery & RESTful APIs using Node.js and C#
- Slashed 90% team efforts by automating multi-step ETL processes for preprocessing large datasets using SSIS
- Designed site usage analytics dashboards using Power BI and Applications Insights with summarizing visualizations for 10+ KPIs
- Lowered 30% time for data verification by automating testing solution using C# and T-SQL
- Developed Continuous Integration (CI) and Continuous Deployment (CD) for backend solutions using SSIS
- Reduced site load time by 50% by deploying the sites to content delivery networks
- Boosted run-time performance by analysis of query execution plan, implementing indexes and other performance tuning measures
- Identified, analysed and resolved software bugs during testing and production stages

- Administered multiple roles and their data access by implementing database security and authentication measures
- Deployed frontend and service solutions on Azure Portal
- Provided round-the-clock support for deployed solutions to worldwide users

Education

Naveen Jindal School of Management, UT Dallas Master of Science - MS, Information Technology and Management · (2017 - 2019)

Institute of Technology, Nirma University

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Information Technology · (2012 - 2016)

C. C. Shah Sarvajanik High School 12th, Mathematics and Computer Science · (2010 - 2012)

H.M.B. Sardar High School 8th-10th, High School/Secondary Diplomas and Certificates · (2008 - 2010)